Guide to the Marion Barry 1978 campaign oral history project collection, 1975-2018 MS2342
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Interviews, 2015-2017; Series 1
  - Raskin, Jamie, 2016 September 09; Series 1
    Jamie Raskin was 15 years old the summer of 1978 when he worked for Marion Barry's election as Mayor of DC. At the time of this interview, he is a three-term Democratic State Senator in Maryland and the Senate Majority Whip. A professor of constitutional law at American University's Washington College of Law for the last 25 years, Jamie has also taught at Yale Law School. On April 26, 2016, in an energetic grassroots campaign, Jamie captured the Democratic nomination for Congress in Maryland's District 8 and in January 2017 he took his seat in the U.S. House of Representatives.
  - Robinson, Robert, 2015 August 21; Series 1
    Rob Robinson had extensive national political organizing experience when he joined the 1978 Barry campaign. He assisted Campaign Manager Ivanhoe Donaldson as both a ward coordinator and with multiple administrative tasks. He served in the Barry administrations as Chief Administrative Officer in the Executive Office of the Mayor and chose to leave the government in 1988. Thereafter he did quantitative and qualitative research for an ad agency and ran successful campaigns for DC City Councilmembers. He ran unsuccessfully for the Council himself in 1997. He and his wife, Sherrill, are founding members of DC Solar United Neighborhoods and in 2016 re-established the DC Consumer Utility Board.
  - Rowe, Audrey, 2015 October 16; Series 1
    Audrey Rowe was a Republican and Chairwoman of the National Women's Political Caucus when she had her first experience of grassroots politics working on Marion Barry's 1978 campaign. In Marion's first administration she was Special Assistant for Youth Affairs, devised the plan to establish the Mayor's Youth Leadership Institute and was Director of the Social Services Administration. After leaving District government she had a varied and distinguished career. At the time of this interview, she was Administrator for Food and Nutrition Services at the US Department of Agriculture.
  - Schott, Peter, 2016 September 15; Series 1
    Peter Schott was active in DC Democratic politics for many years. At various times he was a member of the DC Democratic State Committee, the chairman of the Ward 1 Democrats and a delegate to Democratic National Conventions. He was active in several GLBT political organizations, numerous civic associations and has held office in Americans for Democratic Action. He was appointed by Mayor Barry to the DC Human Rights Commission.
  - Seldon, Patricia, 2017 August 09; Series 1
    Pat Selden came to the District in 1951 and worked at various jobs in the federal government, including a stint in the White House. After the first home rule election in 1974, she joined Councilmember Barry's staff. In 1979, when Barry became Mayor, she became his valued Executive Assistant and the gatekeeper to the Mayor's office.
  - Thomas, Romaine, 2015 October 16; Series 1
    Romaine Thomas had a distinguished career in the DC Public School System, including a long tenure as Principal of Ketchum Elementary School. She and her husband Harry, who later became the Ward 5 City Councilman, were active in political and civic affairs in their ward. In 1978, she coordinated Barry's campaign in Ward 5, as she did for all his campaigns.
  - Tucker, Sterling, 2017 September 05; Series 1
    Sterling Tucker was the first Chairman of the DC Council after the establishment of Home Rule in 1974. He was one of the candidates for Mayor in the election of 1978. He came to DC in 1956 to head up the local chapter of the Urban League, a job he performed with great distinction. He was a tireless crusader for civil rights, especially the desegregation of Washington, DC, and for Home Rule. He was a member of the DC Council which was appointed by the US President prior to Home Rule.
- Paper records and artifacts, 1975 - 2015; Series 2
  This series contains buttons, reports, needle point, publications, photographs, and t-shirts related to the 1978 Marion Barry campaign for mayor as well as some other materials from the Barry era documenting aspects of D.C. political history. The bulk of these records date from 1975 - 1985.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Ed Meyers (2017.029) Gift of Betty King (2017.030) Gift of Richard Maulsby (2017.031) Gift of Ethel Delaney Lee (2017.058) Gift of Milton Coleman (2017.061)
  Arrangement
  Arranged in aphabetical order by donor name.
  - Milton Coleman donation: D.C. Mayoral campaign brochures, fliers, bumper stickers and photograph, Circa 1978; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Milton Coleman donation: Political buttons, 1978; Series 2 (Flat box 3)
    Political buttons from the 1978 DC mayor campaign and from a special election the following year to fill the at-large DC Council seat vacated by Marion Barry. There are also buttons for the 1978 September 12 election for DC Council chairman, Dixon vs. Moore.
  - Betty King donation: buttons and needle point pins for Marion Barry campaigns, one Polly Shackleton needle point pin, Circa 1978; Series 1 (Flat box 4)
  - Betty King donation: needle point artifacts, Circa 1978; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Betty King donation: photographs, 1978; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    General
    Images include Marion Barry and Betty King at a Women for Barry luncheon and Betty King and Bob Washington, Chair of the DC Democratic State Committee
  - Betty King donation: photograph, 1979 February; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Framed image of Marion Barry with the staff of the Executive Office of the Mayor. The back of the image includes a list identifying those in the image row by row.
  - Betty King donation: Cartoon by Vint Lawrence sold as a fund raiser for the 1978 Barry Campaign, Series 2 (Flat box 2, Item 2)
  - Betty King donation: framed item with several images related to the 1978 Barry campaign, Circa 1978 - 1999; Series 2 (Flat box 2, Item 3)
  - Betty King donation: [notes for planned interview with Ivanhoe Donaldson], 2015; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    In 2015, Julius Hobson and Diane Lewis met with Ivanhoe Donaldson to discuss videotaping an interview with him for the oral history project. Donaldson had been the Campaign Manager for Barry's 1978 mayoral campaign and was an immensely influential force in Barry's life. Donaldson was already seriously ill with the cancer which ultimately killed him. After an extensive conversation to map out the outlines of the interview, he was only able to record a very brief segment. He never felt well enough to schedule a further recording session. Hobson has provided these notes on the issues they planned to cover in the aborted interview.
  - Betty King donation: newspaper articles and other press related to Marion Barry (1978 election and other political work), 1979-2017; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ethel Delaney Lee donation: fliers and other written materials, 1978; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Richard Maulsby donation: Gertrude Stein Democratic Club and DC political materials, 1978-1985; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ed Meyers donation: Revenue Strategies for the District of Columbia, 1975 March 06; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ed Meyers donation: Report of the Committee on Finance and Revenue on the Revenue Act of 1975, 1975 July 11; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ed Meyers donation: Outlook for the District fiscal year 1977 and Beyond Budgeting Under Suburban Economic Domination, 1975 December 16; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ed Meyers donation: News release: Marion Barry announces major three-part property tax reduction program for D.C. homeowners and renters, 1977 November 11; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ed Meyers donation: news release Barry acts to provide real property tax relief, 1978 April 19; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ed Meyers donation: T-shirts, Circa 1978; Series 2 (Flat box 2, Item 1)
    One t-shirt reads: "Making a profound difference right now! Marion Barry, Jr. Mayor" the other t-shirt reads "Operating Services Assisting Youth"
- WTOP program "The Making of Marion Barry" a three part program., 2018 November; Series 3; 13 digital object(s)
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Thsi series contains the recorded interviews and transctipts. These interivew were conducted by Rick Massimo, Digital Writer/Editor, WTOP for the program "The Making of Marion Barry." The interviewees included Betty King, Tom Sherwood, Absalom Jordan, Denise Rolark Barnes, Latoya Foster, and Vincent Gray. and pdfs of the text that that accompanied the online portion of the three part radio program.
  - Denise Rolark Barnes interview, Series 3
  - Latoya Foster interview, Series 3
  - Vincent Gray interview, Series 3
  - Absalom Jordan interview, Series 3
  - Betty King interview, Series 3
  - Tom Sherwood interview, Series 3
  - Completed program written text: The making of Marion Barry, parts 1-3, Series 3
    The making of Marion Barry, Part 1: A DC mayor's activist beginnings in the South
    The making of Marion Barry, Part 2: Street activist to power player
    The making of Marion Barry, Part 3: 'There was no way we could win'